okay great
thank you um we hope to have a great
fireside chat with dr sima rao
um dr seema
at an age of 1920 when most women were
busy while away time in the college
canteens or shopping or obsessing over
the boyfriends that they might have you
were training for shooting and as well
as black belt please tell us how are you
doing that at such a young age
okay to uh
just go back into my childhood first and
foremost let me just wish all of you a
very happy woman's day
uh now i come back to my story uh so i
was
in school i was weak and bullied as a
child
so i really didn't like that and i
wanted to change that equation so as i
grew up
i decided that i should make myself
strong
the only way i could think of making my
self strong was to learn martial art
in college
um as uh in medical college i met
my future husband so we were both
studying medicine
and cupid was at work so
we we fell in love and he was pursuing
martial art as a hobby
so that's when i realized that probably
i should also be doing this so that i
get strong and powerful and learn to
take care of myself
and i started learning from him and we
decided to get married early so and
settle down and start our life
so he got married and i had spent about
two years two or three years in the arts
when there was this uh incident that
happened on cho party
uh we used to go every day in the
morning to chop party and we used to do
our morning training and after that
proceed to college
so it was one of those days when we went
and we were finishing with that training
when there were these three rack pickers
who were passing by
and they said some they passed some
really lewd remarks about me and said
some very demeaning things to me
so uh we just let it go because we were
training and we didn't want to put a
stop to our training um finished as soon
as we finished our training we were
walking towards that direction
uh we saw them uh standing there these
three rack pickers and
my husband said okay so that's your
fight
now i was obviously very scared because
there were three of them and i didn't
know what would happen
so as i
started moving in that direction i
quickly
moved fast because i said let me just
get over with this and uh get back home
so like as i was walking these three
guys one of them came and stood in front
of me so i was looking down so i shifted
left he came and stood in front of me
again i shifted right
he came and stood in front of me so
there's no way out for me so i slowly
looked up and i looked at his face
what i saw on his face was something i
did not like i saw underestimation on
his face and i saw the expression that
uh
you're just a woman what can you do
i don't know what came over me and i
just lifted my hand and i slapped him
hard across the face
he got enraged and he came straight at
me trying to headbutt me so you know
they they hit their head on your nose so
as he came charging towards me i moved
back and i lifted my knee and he got a
hard shot on his head so he kind of got
concussed meanwhile his friend took out
his a knife and just opened it and
slashed it across my body
uh the knife cut my t-shirt but not my
skin i caught hold of him and i you know
punched him i threw him on the ground
uh in some time there were a lot of
people who gathered there and then i
just moved out of that place
but i think that was the first time i
realized what it was to change from
weakness to strength
and what it was to now feel like someone
who is in control of her life
and not just about being controlled by
circumstance or life
so that was a turning point in my life
when i realized that
that there are some times when you need
to take charge
of your life and you need to change
what you're destined to be
amazing and
i'm guessing this was before the
pre-viral sensation days otherwise had
this happened in the recent scenario we
would have had this on camera and this
would have been a viral sensation a
woman kicking ass with three rag figures
awesome
so coming to your combat training and
that to a close
combat training with commandos
nonetheless right um they epitomize and
embody everything that you stand for
with extreme physical fitness rigor
discipline bringing the enemy down to
its knees fighting terrorism
it's very unconventional and unique as a
career choice or as a profession
how is it that you came about the
commando training could you tell us yeah
so basically my subject is close quarter
battle so close quarter battle is uh
when you fight the enemy at close
quarters
which means about 30 yards or extendable
200.
uh so our current counter terrorism
scenario is a lot to do with close
quarter battle so close quarter battle
uh includes many subjects
one is armed and unarmed combat
the second one is being able to shoot
the third one is team on team tactics
and the fourth is close quarter battle
simulation exercises so there are many
components to a close quarter battle
now um i was good in uh my unarmed
combat and i had got a black belt and
things like that but apart from that uh
as a kid i read a lot of stories on uh
you know a lot of comic you know the
commando comics that were there and i
was always very thrilled about the life
of commandos
yeah but it was like a very fascinating
kind of vocation to have a profession to
have
so anyways as i grew up you know all
that just got forgotten because you get
so involved with your studies and you
know routine stuff
but my um combat skills were still on
and there was this chance meeting i had
with a very senior official
who happened to see my skills and he was
very impressed so he said why don't you
please come and give a demonstration to
my force so i went and i gave a
demonstration after that he was
impressed even further he said why don't
you train my force so i said okay so i
started training his force and then you
know things just happened and from one
force to the other and i was invited by
service jeeps and
25 years just passed i i honed up my
skills i i wanted to know as a commando
a commando is very comfortable in
sea under the sea in on land as well as
in the air
so i did various courses on survival
sailing parasailing you know scuba
diving
because i as well as uh the jumps etc
and mountaineering and things like that
because i wanted to understand the
scenario in which a commando that's his
terrain
so that is what would make me understand
the job better and of course i had my
skills and credentials so coupled with
both these things i was able to
do a good job
good job is an underestimate
um i'm curious to know as a woman did
you ever face bias while you were
training the commanders
okay how did you overcome that
my field of work is a physical one so
when i go and face the trainees
uh it's uh you know you have to lead by
personal example
so uh if i had to shoot i had to take
them on the firing range and make them
shoot a different way of shooting
i had to pick up the weapon myself and
show my shooting skills
if it was unarmed combat i would box
with them wrestle with them so anything
that i had to do i had to get on you
know you know show it by doing it myself
any kind of task that i had to do and i
think once i would do that there would
be there would be a respect that
would be there in their minds and they
knew that
i was there
capable of teaching them
and they knew i was the boss
yeah the she boss
[Applause]
you also have gone through some very
tough episodes with injuries with your
vertebrae being fractured
with head trauma
in fact it left you with amnesia i
believe
and bedridden for almost six months
how did you overcome such a traumatic
phase and did you ever think about this
is it
there's no more i'm quitting
yeah so there was uh i was
training a force where i decided to do a
monkey rope across two buildings and
this was at a height of about 40 feet
and usually we don't use those safety
nets and all that because it has to be
realistic what they're going to do is
there's not going to be any net there
so this was a height of 40 feet and i
was traversing from one side to the
other so there were two buildings and i
was there's a rope across
so i held on to the rope so monkey rope
is where you hold that open you have a
legs around and then you're moving from
one side to the other
so as i moved for some reason the rope
snapped
and it came straight down now i knew
that if i would have just left my hands
because it happens is you suddenly get a
joke i knew if i would leave my hands
i'd go straight down 40 feet and that
would be the end of me so so i held on
to the rope tightly and as i came down
my back hit the wall of the building
and i heard a crack in my back and my
vertebrae had broken
but i still held on tightly and very
soon there were people they came and i
was moved to the hospital i took quite
some months to recover from that
the second
episode was when
i heard about i was at a force training
them in unarmed combat
and it was a grappling session that was
happening
the session was just about to end when
one soldier came and
told me that my father had expired
so
i was still in session so i couldn't
obviously show my emotions so i said
okay and i continued
and
i was grappling with one guy then taking
him
lifting him dropping him down on his
back
and i was about to end the session and
then suddenly one um
of the trainees said that
i'm you know i want to grapple with you
i uh sensed a certain challenge in his
voice
so i said okay fine let's uh let me just
finish with this i'm almost at the end
of the session so
and he uh but i think i had lost my
focus
so after a while he lifted me up and
threw me on the ground hard landed on my
head
i was knocked out
cold
then i ended up in the hospital and
when i
regained consciousness i realized that
i had just it was like a memory delete
you know all your memories just deleted
and i was wondering who i am where i am
and things like that it's it's a
terrible feeling to have
but uh gradually as my memory came back
and as i got better which took quite
some time quite some months
but i uh do i distinctly remember during
both these situations when i would lie
down
and look at the the white ceiling of the
hospital room i would ask myself
uh maybe it's enough maybe this is the
time to stop i've done enough i've spent
enough number of years training the
forces done all kinds of difficult tasks
so maybe i should just uh you know stop
but you know i didn't want to be
an 80 year old woman who would look in
the mirror and uh
find a coward there looking back at me
and i said that no this is not what i'm
gonna i'm not going to
quit
i'm not going to leave whatever i'm
doing i'm going to do this thing
yes i'm going to be cautious about it so
i decided to be cautiously bold
in the sense that i would do dangerous
tasks but i would be very cautious about
what could go wrong etc and that made it
a lot more easier
so
that's how i could handle it because i
think you know in in life
there are situations which bog you down
and pull you down and where everyone
around you also says maybe it's time to
just stop you've been doing it so that's
enough to shake your conviction
but it is at that time where you need to
to really look within you need to say no
it happens it it it's never a it's never
a rosy uh you know path for any of us
but somewhere we got to put in that
extra push and that extra fight
thank you for sharing such an emotional
personal account
and we can well imagine how tough it
must have been for you
um i also know that um your father was a
freedom fighter so obviously this just
never giving up
you know the passion the resilience the
sense of honor and duty that you have
for serving the country you get that
running in your blood yeah so tell us
how it was uh growing up with the father
and his experiences how did that shape
you and influence you yeah so my father
was a freedom fighter and uh as a child
i grew up listening to a lot of stories
from him about his participation in the
freedom struggle
and
there were stories there was this one
story where he was imprisoned and he was
in a jail
you know put by by the portuguese and
he escaped from the jail with a fellow
inmate
swam across the manduvi river
moved to safety and then continued with
the freedom struggle
he would write a lot of
inflammatory propaganda against the
portuguese
he was an underground rebel
and all these stories that he would tell
me would i would be really fascinated
you know it was a it made a very huge
impact on my childlike mind
and i thought that if if life gave me an
opportunity even i too should do
something for the country
and i think you know sometimes when you
have this deep desire to do something
then i think life just opens up and you
know gives you that one opportunity
which you
are looking for and then you go
grab that opportunity and uh you know
move in the direction of your passion
well said
um a little less known fact for all of
you uh that dr sima has been training
over 20 000 commandos special forces
over the last 20 25 years but she's done
this all without a dime completely free
of any compensation
tell us dr sima how did you
how did you come about giving that much
of yourself and your entire life your
youth
uh to the country with the sense of
honor and duty but without any monetary
rewards
i i do understand that money is very
important to buy us the comforts and the
luxuries of life
there's no doubt about that but i think
for me uh then honor and duty was
something that was very important
because probably of the the kind of
childhood and the uh influence that was
there on my mind
so we would travel my husband and i
would travel to uh various different
locations
he would be at one place i would be
somewhere else
and we were traveling almost eight
months in a year so
uh you know
and we didn't want to charge the forces
because it was a question of wanting to
do work
and uh honorable work and contribute to
the soldiers and you know the people who
are safeguarding our country
so in a way we decided that let's put
that aside and just do what we want to
do and it was very interesting word
challenging work and respectable work
there was no doubt that it was hard
because when we would come back home it
would be difficult to survive so i would
sell off some we would sell off for gold
and you know my fixed deposits are fixed
deposits you try to dissolve them and
live that way but there was no doubt
about uh
though we were you know going bankrupt
many times
but i think the sense of duty and the
sense the passion that was there i think
that is what
you know was way above
anything else so we just carried on
[Applause]
how many of us can actually say or do
this right with a sense of honor and
duty for the country
i know that she came close to even
selling her mangal sutra and became
bankrupt and for a woman to part with
something
it just tells us about the spirit of
patriotism that is so hard
i i yeah i like to say one thing that
for me
for any one of us actually a mangal
is
a symbol of
marriage in the sense partnership
with somebody who is going to lead his
life with you
so for me the mangal sutra was
was there very much with its
significance but i was working with my
husband we had the same dreams we had
the same passions
uh we were walking together hand in hand
suffering together
smiling together you know everything was
together so the manga didn't i mean what
we were doing was what a manga suta
makes you do so that's why uh he had an
eye injury once so i decided that okay
it's time for the manga sutra to go
because he has to undergo the surgery so
tell us when you
thank you
when you were receiving the nari shakti
award for the highest civilian
woman owner from none other than the
president of india yes what was that
feeling like what was that emotion
you know i i trained the forces
going doing my job coming back
uh not really looking for any fame any
awards or anything of that kind
so while this was happening one day i
was pleasantly surprised when i got a
call from the president's office
and they said that you have to come to
rashtrapati bhavan and you have to take
your award and you have been nominated
you know for the award and i was
i took some time to believe uh the news
and i was like okay this is actually
happening okay fine as it sunk in i
obviously was very happy and i i felt it
was um it was very nice to be that my
work was acknowledged by
the highest office in the country
and i went and i took the
award from the president it was a proud
moment for me no doubt
and
one of the moments best moments of my
life
speaking of awards we know that you have
won a lot of coveted awards
but you
embody
and epitomize
not just brawn
and not just brains but also beauty
you were a runner up in mrs india world
beauty pageant how did that come about
okay so
um there was this mrs india uh beauty
pageant that was it was from mrs india's
so usually you know you only think it's
all about miss india and then once
you're married like you're not you're
not gonna be you know considered for
that so there's this mrs india beauty
pageant that was introduced so it was it
was like everyone was wondering okay
what is all this
so some of our friends who are from the
forces they uh spoke to us
and they said that
come on you know same i should go and uh
you know enroll in that
so i said look just forget all that you
know i'm comfortable with my camo boots
and my uniform and
that i'm an action person forget about
all this they said no no nothing doing
you know so my husband quietly went
filled up one form and then i received a
call
and they said please come
you know just come and we'll interview
and that's it so i went there
and
the they interviewed me and i just spoke
they said ma'am can you just walk from
here today i just walked i came back
home
and i said okay it's over thank god like
and then uh
surprisingly after a few days they said
please come you you have to come for the
training and you're part of the old mrs
india thing so i went there i've met a
lot of other women and um you know
they were coming from different places
all over the country talking about their
lives
and it was nice spending time just like
seven days of training which we had
which culminated in the
pageant
and
it was a good it was different okay it
was a different color of life compared
to what i was doing
and then finally i walked the ramp and
at the end of the ramp i went and i said
why do the same thing they do i'll do
something different so i flexed my
biceps
and turned
so
and yeah and i was
but it was uh it was a nice color of
life because there are so many colors to
life
but
it didn't in any way take me away from
what my core
work was that this is what i have to do
and that's nice but
yeah it just shows the multi facets of
your personality
and now we know that brawn physical
prowess is you know next level but
there's beauty as well at that too at a
world pageant level but she has also
authored multiple books
including the first encyclopedia on
close uh combat and i think that sits
proudly in the shells of fbi
interpol
um swag libraries yes
so tell us how did you author uh these
books and
you know what was that experience
so uh training the courses we had some
out of the box ideas on training which
we're obviously sharing with the forces
so we decided to write a book on this
and again for this we did not take any
sponsorships donations or grants for the
book
we used our lives earnings and came up
with the book
and we gave it to the defense ministry
and the home ministry it was gifted to
them so that the book could go to every
academy and be in the libraries of you
know so that people could use it
and apart from that
i also send the book to the fbi and the
interpol and the swat libraries all over
the world
the book was received very well and i
received letters of appreciation from
the chiefs
of all these organizations saying it is
a very good book and it has found a
proud place in their libraries
so uh it was one of the very few books
you know written and that's written by
an indian so
so that was
and i'm sure they referred to it while
filming 24 series
um
dr seema
uh we know that your work depends a lot
on your physical
fitness and regime given that
um you know if there's close combat on
ground training
special forces
so do you believe with age obviously you
know with the body is not as young and
youthful as energetic
uh can you share some um you know
experience from your diet fitness regime
uh what is it that you do to defy age to
stay at the top of your game
okay uh
yeah the age has a way of seeping into
your system and uh you know
making you realize that uh okay now
you're not as good as you were so it's
constantly a fight okay
and you need to keep fighting
when it comes to my diet i would say
that
i strictly follow a no oil diet i'm very
careful because oil just goes and you
know messes up a perfect body so i try
to avoid oil as much as possible i take
a high protein diet
i have a alkaline juice which is a
lockheed juice every day because it's
it's extremely alkaline and it kind of
you know it moves in your joints and it
keeps you healthy so that is one
investment i make towards good health
apart from the no oil and the high
protein lockheed juice people yes take
notes yes
and
apart from that i run twice a week about
two and a half kilometers or five
kilometers
and i wait train and
i do my combat stuff
and i have an academy uh so every
saturday sunday i go there to the
academy
i fight with men who are half my age
twice my weight
and i put them in a real bad mess
i love it how she says it's so matter of
factly you know
it's awesome
so um is there a message especially on
international women's day that you would
like to leave for all the
women in this room who are listening to
you for all our remote offices
but even to the women in general
yeah i'd like to say that
a woman is
shakti
all of these embodied into you
shakti is power there is power or latent
power inside every woman
saraswati if you educate yourself you
will get economically independent
and lastly
lakshmi
wealth
prosperity
so once you are able to educate yourself
empower yourself
make your own money
then i don't think you need anybody else
in the world
second i would say that
as a woman
you should keep upgrading your skills
that's what i have done don't stagnate
at whatever level you are at but keep
upgrading your skills to courses etc
thirdly i'd say that take criticism in a
healthy fashion
because a lot of times when people
criticize you
you are
you know too biased you feel like okay
it's the end of the world and i'm no
good
but it's just yeah and it but it's just
one quality probably which is being uh
criticized
and i would say that you need to work so
so objectively try to analyze whether
really you need to correct that and if
you think you need to correct that
objectively after an objective analysis
then work on that quality be obsessed
with wanting to change that quality
about yourself
be a self-critic
okay don't don't uh wait for other
people to tell you what your mistake is
look at yourself make an assessment
probably a monthly or a yearly
assessment of what your attributes are
positive and negative and where you need
to go so your negative attributes you
need to work on them you need to be
obsessed with getting over with them
that obsession is very important if you
want to succeed if you want to win
it so you you have to eradicate all the
negative qualities inside you and fill
yourself constantly with positives
and it's only then that you're going to
keep going ahead keep going up keep
happy all of that
uh um
is anything else um
yeah
i was just wondering whether i mean
there are a lot of things but uh i think
these would be the main ones no i think
you've spoken and
tried to encapsulate and i know it's a
very large message for women there's one
more thing i'm going to say
um that is that uh a woman is basically
in
yin is uh
you know the qualities that yin actually
symbolify our
softness adaptability
understanding
all this is a woman
whereas we consider man
the yang aspect of a man is all about
you know dominance drive aggression
now if a woman also cultivates a little
bit of yang in her personality
so i'm not saying change from yin to
yang i'm saying keep the softness in you
you're a woman it's it's a it's an
active attribute so keep the softness
the
the you know adaptability the
understanding nature but add a little
bit of yang which is drive aggression
assertion all of that in you
now this is a winning combination
whereas on the other side a man has only
yang
so he should also have a little bit of
yin now the yin and yang when they get
together it's a complete one circle
so in fact at a work uh you know in the
work atmosphere if a man and woman work
together it's a yang and yin combination
so both let me say they said women to
have their own qualities which a man
does not have so use those qualities
there are distinctly different qualities
which women have
and add a little bit of the yang in you
and i think it's a wonderful combination
extremely well captured
and in fact you've answered my uh
leading question to that was what was
the message that you'd have for the men
uh you know and the role that they want
to play um
as protagonists of the women in their
life
um and while you've said for the yang
energy to embody a bit of the yin energy
but is there something that you'd like
to say to the men out there who still
believe and you know some of these
biases on stereotypes are so
conditioned you know preconditioned
deep rooted or is there anything that
you'd like to say towards that bias and
stopping that bias
first and foremost i like to just talk
about my
relating with my husband i don't like to
call him my husband i like to call him
my life partner
okay
because
marriage as an institution
does have a little
its negatives as well so i won't go into
that but
but let me say that the relationship for
another session yeah
so uh when a man and woman uh relate as
a man and wife
okay they should be interested in
helping each other to reach their
maximum potential so while you help your
husband uh reach his you know dreams
you you should also assert to your
husband that he should help you to
realize your dreams so it's a win-win
situation for both of you
uh apart from that at the i i think uh
i have met
uh people men okay
who have been uh
see i'm let me talk about myself i'm not
a feminist in the sense anti-men no i
believe that many people many males are
very uh
balanced and understand the qualities in
a woman
there may be few people who are not like
that
but
for those few people probably i'll say
that one needs to understand that a
woman also has her own capabilities and
you need to give her a chance to show
those capabilities
if you do that it's going to be a
winning combination again because like i
said a man and woman working together a
man has it his attributes a woman has
her attributes bring them together and
success is a sure short thing
great
thank you so much dr simaro i'm sure the
audience here has questions for you
would anybody like to
i'm opening the floor to questions
yeah sure
very simple question uh doctor is
being a doctor and now we're in a very
different profession
how was the decision
to shift have you really i'm sure you're
not practicing anymore you're practicing
something else
yeah but you know what the study of
medicine uh is something that i did use
in my uh combat training because it's
also about you know maiming crippling
killing the enemy so how do you know
where to do it so that's where the study
of medicine helped me
to come up with you know certain places
areas vital areas in the body where if
you attack somebody it could really
or name or kill so
apart from that the study of medicine is
also for self because you know what's
happening
when you are having what trouble and how
to deal with it so uh
yeah
this was a lethal combination you used
both yes
the first one is you mentioned about the
fight you were having with a person you
know when you it was declared that you
didn't have your father so he's showing
your emotional side a weak uh stuff you
said you didn't want to show it the
talking of the way the trainee lifted me
and where you got your
head yeah you mentioned that you came to
know that your father expired and you
didn't want to show your emotional side
the women are known to show our
emotional side so is it wrong to show
your emotional side that's it no it's
not wrong to show your emotional side at
all
i think
crying feeling sad
uh does not mean you're not tough
but what i was trying to say is that i
was in the middle of a session now
obviously when you're standing in the
middle of a session you need to have
some kind of resolve that okay let me
finish with this and after that let me
let me drown in my own sorrow
unfortunately i didn't even get to do
that because i fell on my head and then
i woke up days later
so my morning period was
after that so in any case so
nothing is wrong i think even if a man
cries
doesn't make him weak if a woman cries
doesn't make her weak
it's just an emoting of your feelings
that is there
it's not related to weakness
second question is why don't we have
more like you in the country
there are many of you in this country
only you don't know it
yeah we don't have any other woman
commando trainer you're
right yeah but i'm uh
i'm just a set of qualities
okay
and principals
one of a kind no
i want to say that that every woman here
has her attributes
so uh it's just for you to to realize
what they are it's just for you to not
be afraid to do something new because a
lot of times fear is a very big thing
that blocks our path we're afraid to do
something new because we think we'll
fail but i think that's something which
should be changed it's okay if you fail
so what at least you tried
so and many times when you try you don't
fail you actually don't fail
when did you realize that you are a good
friend
trainer of commanders you're saying
right in any case i mean
knowing it doing it yourself
it happens
it's the magical touch
yeah yeah it just happens
so throughout when you were speaking i
noticed that you have a visibly very
calm persona
and i have never seen you i mean when we
hear about anybody from this kind of a
profession
we generally have in mind
you know aggressive aggressive
personality
so
is it is that i mean that came across as
a contradiction okay so
how is that you maintain that because
your work is little aggressive but you
have amazingly docile and calm persona
see aggression needs to be
used
at the right time
you don't need to waste your aggression
which is within you
so when i need to be aggressive i'm
aggressive but otherwise i'm cool why
should i change my personality for
anything in the world
so
that's how it works for me
only when the situation demands it
[Applause]
and i think more important than
aggression is assertion
an assertion is something which is more
easier but a lot of people find it
difficult
so if you can assert for your rights if
you can assert for what you don't think
is right
all of that
that's good enough you don't need to be
aggressive
yeah my academy deals with the corporate
men and women who come on the weekend
because the rest of the days they are
too tied up with their
jobs
so uh it's it's a holistic
you know academy in the sense that
you're taught fitness you're taught
about the mind
there are certain combat programs a lot
of things
so and it's on the weekends it's in
andheri
i
want you to understand one thing you
mentioned that you were invited your
first training instance you were invited
by one of the chiefs to train
his set of commandos
prior to that you were training i
believe like you just said corporates
how is it different and your first
experience actually training commandos
uh how were you perceived
as a you know woman when you went to
train uh commandos who
have this perception saying they have
already been trained by the toughest men
on the job and then you had to go and
you can actually give them a training or
a demo
how is that experience for the first
time
and how is it different when you train
corporates versus the commandos i don't
train uh you mean train corporates in
the academy yes so let me talk about the
commandos first
like i said that i lead by uh personal
example so that's how uh
i'm not concerned with how they see me
i'm concerned with how
i do my thing
a lot of times it is you're more aware
of
what people are thinking about you but i
think that should be really scrapped out
you just be bothered about how you're
doing your stuff and do it to the best
of your ability and people see and
people respect
second is a certain degree of respecting
your own self so when you respect
yourself people respect you
so that's how i went about training the
commandos and
like i said i also had to own up my
skills etc
when it comes to training corporates
it's a different program so it's done a
lot of times by the people who are under
me running my setup in my academy
so
i i'm the
the director of the academy
do you have any more questions
okay
before we let you go and i know this is
a complete surprise
attack okay
i'm used to dealing with all kinds we'll
just have a quick but first whether it's
an attack or not
it's a verbal attack with the rapid fire
um and i'm i'm literally thinking on the
fly um give me one word the first word
that association that you associate with
whatever i ask country
no i'll ask and then you give me okay i
thought you already started no
here goes
country
life
i've i've given my life
so life itself is yeah
passion
fighting
success
everything
balance
women
strength
fame
now that's not gonna be
okay
okay great thank you so much dr seema
um this has been such a wonderful
wonderful experience
um you've left us enriched enlightened
uh with such great rich experience of
yours and insights that we will all mull
over not just today but in the days to
come
um thank you so much
especially on this day today that you
know you stand for
everything that a woman would like to be
and wants to be so thank you so much for
inspiring not just